Farah Samy Mohamed

eng.farah.samy@gmail.com | 01012808563 | https://github.com/eng-farah-samy | https://www.linkedin.com/in/farahsamy | 15 Gameel Thabeet ST, moharm beh, Alexandria, Egypt

Summary

My names Farah Samy Mohamed I am 23 years old and Got my bachelor's in management information system from Faculty of Business English Section . I have a great knowledge of Data and Business and I expanded my skills when I chose the Data analysis Career to analyze this data to get better insights.

As a data analyst, I am committed to using data to help organizations optimize their operations, improve their products and services, and achieve their strategic goals. I have a strong background in statistics, programming, and data visualization, I am skilled in using a variety of tools and technologies, including SQL, Python, R, Tableau, and Excel.

Experience

october 2023 – now

Data Analyst Specialist at Misr Amreya Spinning & Weaving Co. s.a.e. . Full-time

Alexandria, Egypt · On-site

- Analyzed inventory levels and compared them against sales trends to ensure optimal stock management.
- Managed purchasing processes and conducted tenders for new fabrics, focusing on the highest-selling items.
- Forecasted sales and developed marketing strategies/campaigns based on seasonal and period-based insights.
- Monitored production operations, evaluated machine performance, and investigated downtime causes to improve efficiency.

Sep 2023 -April 2024

Data Analyst Specialist at Joprogrammer . Full-time

Canada · Remote

Certificate of Employment 🔗



- Collecting and organizing data and make all the Statistical Analysis on it
- Analyzing the data to identify trends and insights that can inform improvements
- Creating Automatic Daily reports Using Power Query to the Company

Jan 2023- Feb 2023

Internship as Research and Development Analyst

At Alexandria Port Authority

- Stored, retrieved, and manipulated data for analysis of system capabilities and
- Analyzed information to determine, recommend and plan new systems and modifications installation.

Projects

Pizza Sales Analysis 🔗

Marketing Analysis 🔗

Global Economic Indicators Dashboard

Sales Dashboard

Cars Sales Analysis

Groceries-Dashboard_

Education

Jun 2023: bachelor's degree in Management Information Systems Department At Faculty of commerce English section

Alexandria University

GPA 3.6 out of 4.

Graduation project

Car craft: a Decision Support System website that helps in choosing the best and suitable car for his usage and needs

This project was done by using frontend & backend such as html, CSS, JavaScript, PHP & Laravel

Courses & Certification

Data analysis associate Certification (DataCamp)

IBM Data Analyst Professional Certificate (IBM-Coursera)

Introduction to Statistics (Stanford University-Coursera)

Advanced Excel (356dntascience)
Pivot Tables in Excel (356dntascience)

Track Data Analyst with Python (36 HOURS) (Data Camp)
Track Data analysis with SQL (39 hours) (DataCamp)

Data visualization (DataCamp)
PowerBI (DataCamp)

Database Fundamentals (MaharaTech-ITIMooca)

Data analyst Challenger Track (Udacity)

Java Foundations Certification (Arab Academy for Science Technology and

Maritime Transport)

- · Java programming
- · Python for data analysis
- Statistics
- Python analysis libraries (NumPy, pandas, Matplotlib, seaborn)
- · Problem-solving
- · Data mining
- · Intelligence Decision support system

- · Data visualization
- · Reporting & analysis
- Databases
- · SQL advanced
- · Decision making
- · Business intelligence
- · Data warehousing
- · Information technology

VOLUNTEER

1- Instructor at (For career Data analysis) Community

The community provides essential support for individuals looking to pursue a career in data analysis, offering opportunities for students to collaborate on projects, share knowledge, and develop their skills together.

2- Technical Organizer At Alexandria University

- Played a key role in ensuring the smooth running of the event.
- Responsibilities included coordinating with speakers, managing technical equipment and infrastructure, and troubleshooting any issues that arose.
 - implemented systems for clients to help each maintain long-term organizational goals.

3- Bank Misr internship 🔗

- I learned Financial analysis And risk management And finance and banking services
- Helped me with informed decision-making by managing risks, funds, and banking operations effectively.